export const chapter = "Chapter - 29: The Judiciary ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the Judiciary often referred to as due to its role in interpreting the Constitution and protecting rights?",
        optionA: "Guardian of Democracy",
        optionB: "Executive Authority",
        optionC: "Legislative Watchdog",
        correctAnswer: "A) Guardian of Democracy",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, what principle does the government operate under in which all people are equal before the law?",
        optionA: "Rule of Power",
        optionB: "Rule of Law",
        optionC: "Rule of Equality",
        correctAnswer: "B) Rule of Law",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why is the Judiciary considered an essential organ of government in India?",
        optionA: "It enforces laws created by the Legislature",
        optionB: "It resolves disputes and provides justice",
        optionC: "It formulates government policies",
        correctAnswer: "B) It resolves disputes and provides justice",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is NOT one of the functions of the Judiciary mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Interpretation of the Constitution",
        optionB: "Enforcing tax regulations",
        optionC: "Resolution of disputes",
        correctAnswer: "B) Enforcing tax regulations",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who has the authority to interpret the Constitution and declare a law null and void if it violates the Constitution?",
        optionA: "The Executive",
        optionB: "The Legislature",
        optionC: "The Judiciary",
        correctAnswer: "C) The Judiciary",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the highest level of the judiciary in India, according to the text?",
        optionA: "High Courts",
        optionB: "Supreme Court",
        optionC: "Subordinate Courts",
        correctAnswer: "B) Supreme Court",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the context of the Indian judicial system, what is the purpose of Lok Adalat?",
        optionA: "To enforce criminal laws",
        optionB: "To speed up the resolution of cases",
        optionC: "To interpret the Constitution",
        correctAnswer: "B) To speed up the resolution of cases",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, what is the doctrine that separates the functions of the Legislature, Executive, and Judiciary?",
        optionA: "Separation of Powers",
        optionB: "Unity of Powers",
        optionC: "Division of Powers",
        correctAnswer: "A) Separation of Powers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the abbreviation 'PIL' stand for in the legal context?",
        optionA: "Public Interest Litigation",
        optionB: "Private Investigator License",
        optionC: "Professional Information Laws",
        correctAnswer: "A) Public Interest Litigation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who can file a PIL in India, and what is its primary purpose?",
        optionA: "Only government officials to address bureaucratic issues",
        optionB:
          "Any individual or organization to address issues of public interest",
        optionC:
          "Only those with legal expertise to challenge government actions",
        correctAnswer:
          "B) Any individual or organization to address issues of public interest",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary is often referred to as the ____________ of the Constitution because it interprets and protects the Constitution.",
        options: ["Interpreter", "Guardian", "Enforcer"],
        answer: "Guardian",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, the government operates based on the principle of the 'rule of law,' ensuring that all people are ____________ before the law.",
        options: ["Unique", "Equal", "Superior"],
        answer: "Equal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary plays a key role in keeping the other two government organs in ____________.",
        options: ["Balance", "Authority", "Check"],
        answer: "Check",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Subordinate courts primarily handle cases related to the resolution of ____________ between individuals and organizations.",
        options: ["Agreements", "Conflicts", "Contracts"],
        answer: "Conflicts",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary plays a key role in protecting Fundamental Rights and other rights against ____________ by the government or other entities.",
        options: ["Violation", "Negligence", "Compliance"],
        answer: "Violation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, the judiciary operates at three tiers: the Supreme Court, High Courts, and ____________.",
        options: ["Local Courts", "State Courts", "Subordinate Courts"],
        answer: "Subordinate Courts",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian Judiciary is characterized by an integrated system where all three tiers are ____________ with each other.",
        options: ["Isolated", "Unrelated", "Interconnected"],
        answer: "Interconnected",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In some districts, there may be two different individuals holding the positions of District Judge, one as a Sessions Judge and the other as a ____________ Judge.",
        options: ["Criminal", "Civil", "Appellate"],
        answer: "Civil",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In an ideal scenario, the judge of a court should not be appointed by an ____________.",
        options: ["Advocate", "Officer", "Individual"],
        answer: "Officer",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A PIL can be filed by a poor person using alternative methods, such as a telegram or letter, if they cannot attend the court personally or afford to ____________ an advocate.",
        options: ["Consult", "Appoint", "Hire"],
        answer: "Hire",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary interprets the Constitution and its spirit, protects the rights conferred by the Constitution, and preserves high democratic ideals as enunciated by the Constitution.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, the government does not discriminate between individuals from different backgrounds, castes, religions, languages, regions, or sexes based on the principle of the 'rule of law.'",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary's primary function is to enforce laws created by the Legislature.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Subordinate courts handle cases related to the resolution of agreements between individuals and organizations.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary is responsible for protecting Fundamental Rights, and it has the power to interpret and enforce them.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian Judiciary operates at two tiers: the Supreme Court and the High Courts.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Judiciary in India is not an integrated system, with the three tiers operating independently of each other.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In some districts, there may be two different individuals holding the positions of District Judge, one as a Sessions Judge and the other as a Civil Judge.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Judges in India can be easily removed from their positions once they are appointed.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A Public Interest Litigation (PIL) can be filed only by government officials to address bureaucratic issues.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
